Technical Skills

Strong experience of JavaScript, Backbone, React, Redux, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, HTML5, CSS3, LESS, MYSQL, MongoDB, Git, Java, data structure and algorithm, and testing frameworks..

Also familiar with object oriented programming / design (OOP/D), model-view-controller architecture (MVC), and software as a service (SaaS).

Experience

Yahoo, Lead Software Engineer - 2016 to present

- Monetized Yahoo's owned and operated content, in web and mobile, through the use of the BrightRoll advertising platform.
- Developed the Yahoo video advertisement plugin in video player to inject video ad on video content using JavaScript, and the latest web and ad technology standard.
- Recent achievement: fixed complex and cross ad-system bug that resulted in \$1million per month revenue increase

Banjo, Software Engineer - 2014 to 2016

- Developed high performance enterprise web app, from prototype to production, that organized the world's social and digital signals by location, and empowered media professionals to discover, verify and publish breaking news.
- Developed consumer web app that published breaking news in real time.
- Developed Chrome extension to inject social media posts (Instagram, Twitter, Facebook, and Weibo) into the enterprise web app to complement detected events content.
- Achieved customer base growth from one trial news station, to more than 100+ paying news station customers, and thousands of active media professional users.

Bay Area Javascript Interview Prep Meetup Group, Founder - 2016 to present

• Founded a meetup group (1500+ members) and host meetup weekly to teach data structure and algorithm in JavaScript to software engineers. Link - https://www.meetup.com/Bay-Area-JavaScript-Interview-Prep-Meetup.

JSCrunch, Co-founder - 2016 - 2017

- · Co-founded an online coding platform to practice data structures and algorithms in Javascript. Link jscrunch.com
- Led the product and software development of the coding platform. As a result, the platform is used by the members in the above meetup group that I founded.

Hack Reactor, Software Engineer - 2013 to 2014

Datsy.io

- Led the RESTful APIs design for user to query uploaded CSV file meta data, tag and column. Also, implemented user portal, signup and authentication. Tech stack: Node/Express, Backbone, JugglingDB, Postgres, and Jade.
- APIs were adopted successfully by another team to develop data visualization features.
- Submitted fix to a popular open source ORM, JugglingDB. The fix updated the ORM's spec description in initializing and setting attributes of Postgres table. The fix was accepted and merged to its repo.

CredentialedCare, contracted software engineer

- Developed job marketplace with searching based on geospatial information from scratch for seed funded early stage startup. Tech stack: Node/Express, Angular, MongoDB.
- · Client was very satisfied with the deliverables and planned to demo product to potential investors.
- Customized a popular open source authentication library, Passport to allow for two authentication networks.

Ericsson, ASIC Build Engineer - 2012 to 2013

- Developed and maintained critical internal web app in Perl, HTML, CSS, and MYSQL that was used by 50
 engineers to run more than 10k tests that took 2 weeks to complete. The improved web app provides instant
 information feed and increased visibility on test status.
- Troubleshot regression build failures for the most important piece of networking IC in the Ericsson 4G LTE router that powered Verizon's and AT&T's 4G LTE networks that were used by hundreds of millions wireless customers

Ericsson, ASIC Verification Engineer - 2007 to 2013

- Developed tests using C, assembly language and Linux/UNIX skills to verify homegrown threaded processor that powered the Ericsson 4G LTE router. Strong performance led to promotion.
- Responsible for performance evaluation, optimization, and tuning of the network processor low level software.
- Received multiple awards for top performance (including recognition as top 7% of employees).

Education

Courses: software engineering, introduction to databases, and machine learning (UC Berkeley and Stanford via Coursera), computer architecture, data structure and algorithm.

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN - 2005 to 2007

Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering (Received multiple academic awards)

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN - 2003 to 2005

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Personal Achievements

• Serve as a board of director, translate Buddhism talk to English in real time weekly, and maintain website for True Buddha Vijaya Temple.